{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following bacteria can grow in acidic pH?", "opta": "Vibrio cholerae", "optb": "Lactobacilli", "optc": "Shigella", "optd": "Salmonella", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cell size and cell number can be measured using", "opta": "hemocytometer", "optb": "coulter counter", "optc": "petroff-hausser counting chamber", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used for the proper maintenance and preservation of pure cultures?", "opta": "Periodic transfer to fresh media", "optb": "Preservation by overlaying cultures with mineral oil", "optc": "Preservation by lyophilization", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the process of freeze drying, a dense cell suspension is placed in small vials and is frozen at", "opta": "-60 to -78\u00b0C", "optb": "-20 to -30\u00b0C", "optc": "-30 to -48\u00b0C", "optd": "-48 to -58\u00b0C", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The solidifying agent commonly used in preparation of media is/are", "opta": "agar", "optb": "silica gel", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following chemotherapeutic agents may affect the growth of Campylobacter jejuni?", "opta": "Vacomycin", "optb": "Polymyxin", "optc": "Trimethoprim", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To select cholera-causing bacterium, Vibrio cholerae, the pH of the medium is maintained at a pH of", "opta": "8.5", "optb": "8.90", "optc": "6.79", "optd": "3.5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the selection of endospore-forming bacteria, a mixed culture can be heated at", "opta": "80\u00b0C for 10 minutes", "optb": "70\u00b0C for 10 minutes", "optc": "60\u00b0C for 10 minutes", "optd": "90\u00b0C for 10 minutes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The concentration of agar to obtain semi solid media is", "opta": "1.5-20%", "optb": "0.5% or less", "optc": ">10%", "optd": ">10%but<20%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria dies quickly after drying?", "opta": "Treponema pallidium", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optd": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mac-Conkey medium is an example of", "opta": "transport medium", "optb": "enrichment medium", "optc": "differential medium", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa forms a blue water soluble pigment called", "opta": "pyocyanin", "optb": "chlororaphin", "optc": "pyoverdin", "optd": "\u03b2-carotene", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agar is used for solidifying culture media because", "opta": "it does not affect by the growth of bacteria", "optb": "it does not add to the nutritive properties of the medium", "optc": "the melting and solidifying points of agar solution are not the same", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the selection of lactobacilli present in cheddar cheese, the pH of the medium is maintained at", "opta": "6.35", "optb": "5.35", "optc": "4.35", "optd": "5.75", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A disease producing species occurring in a mixed culture can often be selected on the basis of its", "opta": "pathogenic properties", "optb": "special carbon source", "optc": "special nitrogen source", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Important example(s) of enriched medium/media is/ are", "opta": "Loeffler's serum slope", "optb": "Bordet-gengou medium", "optc": "Blood agar", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cell counting can be carried out by", "opta": "direct microscopic count using petroffhansser counting chamber", "optb": "plate counting", "optc": "membrane filter count", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following techniques may be performed quantitatively to determine the number of bacteria of a particular type?", "opta": "Pour plate", "optb": "Spread plate", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Streak plate technique", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Intestinal bacteria can grow in the presence of __________ whereas nonintestinal bacteria are usually inhibited.", "opta": "bile salts", "optb": "low concentration of various dyes", "optc": "sugars", "optd": "low levels of nitrogen", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following problem makes it impossible to satisfy all of Koch's postulates?", "opta": "Microorganism causes serious symptoms in humans", "optb": "Microorganism cannot be isolated in pure culture", "optc": "Species of microorganism is in question", "optd": "Genes from the microorganism cannot be amplified by PCR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A medium containing crystal violet dye plus sodium deoxycholate will allow", "opta": "gram (-)ve intestinal bacteria to grow", "optb": "gram (+)ve intestinal bacteria to grow", "optc": "aquatic bacteria to grow", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria can grow in alkaline pH?", "opta": "Shigella", "optb": "Lactobacilli", "optc": "Salmonella", "optd": "Vibrio cholerae", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All bacteria that inhabit the human body are", "opta": "heterotrophs", "optb": "chemolithotrophs", "optc": "autotrophs", "optd": "phototroph", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a substance is added to a liquid medium which inhibits the growth of unwanted bacteria and favors the growth of wanted bacteria, it is known as", "opta": "differential medium", "optb": "enriched medium", "optc": "enrichment medium", "optd": "selective medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following methods is most likely to be quantitative?", "opta": "Dilution and plating", "optb": "Gram staining", "optc": "Wet mount", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following hint(s) suggest/s that a given specimen is likely to contain anaerobic bacteria?", "opta": "Gas in specimen", "optb": "Foul odour", "optc": "Presence of sulphur granules", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viable plate count can be obtained using", "opta": "Spread plate method", "optb": "Pour plate method", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Hemocytometer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the pour plate method, the mixed culture is diluted directly in tubes of", "opta": "liquid agar medium", "optb": "sterile liquid usually water", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Treponema species from human oral cavity can be selected by using", "opta": "pH of the medium", "optb": "incubation temperature", "optc": "cell size and motility", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a substance is added to a solid medium which inhibits the growth of unwanted bacteria but permits the growth of wanted bacteria, it is known as", "opta": "differential medium", "optb": "enriched medium", "optc": "enrichment medium", "optd": "selective medium", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptone water and nutrient broth are", "opta": "selective media", "optb": "enriched media", "optc": "basal media", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stuart's transport medium is used for transport of specimen containing", "opta": "Neisseria gonorrhoeae", "optb": "Salmonella", "optc": "Vibrio cholerae", "optd": "Shigella", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plate counts are often reported as", "opta": "cfu", "optb": "cfu/ml", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "thousands/ml", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The medium which allows the growth of more than one microorganisms of interest but with morphologically distinguishable colonies is known as", "opta": "selective medium", "optb": "enrichment medium", "optc": "differential medium", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Selective media facilitate growth of only one kind of organism. Saboraud medium is used to selectively isolate", "opta": "coliform bacteria", "optb": "gram positive bacteria", "optc": "yeasts", "optd": "acid fast organisms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}